profy.com 2007-12-28

# Privacy Policy - Profy.Com

**Privacy Policy**

Welcome to [Profy.com](http://profy.com/), a web site operated by Profy, Inc. This Privacy Policy is presented to inform you about our practices regarding collection, use, and disclosure of information that you may provide via this site. This notice tells you what information we collect, steps we take to protect and secure it, and how we use and share the information. We know that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. This Privacy Policy covers Profy’s treatment of personal information that Profy gathers when you are on the Profy website and when you use Profy services. This policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that Profy does not own or control, or to individuals that Profy does not employ or manage.

You are strongly recommended to read this entire Privacy Policy before submitting links to news stories to or voting and commenting on posts and news stories at Profy. By using the Profy website, you are accepting the practices outlined in this Privacy Policy.

Profy may decide to change this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will post those changes prominently on our web site so that you are always aware of the information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. If there is ever a change to how Profy uses or intends to use personal information, we will post that change to this policy and, if the new policy is materially less restrictive than this policy, we will seek your consent. Please review this Privacy Policy from time to time so that you will be apprised of any changes.

**Information You Provide**

The Profy website actively collects information from its visitors both by allowing you to vote and comment on stories and submit new stories for publication, as well as communicate with us via email. Some of the information that you submit may be personally identifiable information (that is, information that can be uniquely identified with you, such as your e-mail address).

The registration information that you provide us must be validated via email, and we will send you a validation email to that affect.

Your Profy account information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. You need to work to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer by logging off once you have finished using a shared computer.

**Information Collection and Use**

Profy collects personal information when you register with us such as your email address. We use this information solely to validate your registration. When creating your account, we will ask you for a username and password, which will identify you throughout Profy, and your personal email address for account validation. We require this information to create your account and to ensure the validity of the votes and stories you submit to Profy. Profy users can change their password or email information at any time via their profile summary page.

We only collect personal information that is relevant to the purpose of our website. Profy automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, cookies, and the pages you request. Profy uses such information for the following general purposes: services provision, identification and authentication, services improvement, contact, research, and anonymous reporting. Only employees who need personal information to perform a specific job (for example, a customer service representative) are granted access to it.

**Cookies**

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser to enable our system to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages in our website are visited and by how many people. Profy cookies do not collect personal information, and we do not combine information collected through cookies with other personal information to tell us who you are or what your screen name or email address is. We use session cookies and persistent cookies on our web site. Session cookies expire when you logoff and close your browser, while persistent cookies remain on your hard drive for an extended period of time. These cookies are used to identify you as the account holder, and validate your votes and story submissions on the system. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. It will also provide you the directions on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to command the browser to tell you when you receive a new cookie, or how to fully disable cookies. We strongly recommend that you leave the cookies activated, however, because cookies enable you to take advantage of some of Profy’s most attractive features.

**Information Use, Sharing and Disclosure**

Profy does not share personal information we learn about you from your use of the Service or this web site with others except as described in this policy. Profy may use or share your personal information in the following ways:

When you submit a new story, a link to news story, or post a message or comment to public portions of the site, your Profy username (or your real first and last name if you enter them in your profile) may be visible to other users. When you post a new story or comment on a Profy page, you have the ability to post including personally identifiable information about yourself, and that post will be available on the publicly accessible portions of this site. If you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. You must also remember that if you choose not to hide your email in your profile’s options and include other personal information (such as screennames of your internet messengers), it will be thus made public and may also result in unsolicited messages.

Please remember that any information you share in public areas of our web site becomes public, so you should be careful about what you disclose. If you post comments about Profy services on our site, we reserve the right to publish them for editorial purposes or in promotional advertising and/or marketing materials.

Except as otherwise stated, we may internally use information collected via this site to improve the content of our site, to customize the site to your preferences, to communicate information to you (if you have requested it), for our marketing and research purposes, and for any other purpose specified. In addition, we may make full use of all information acquired through this site that is not in personally identifiable form.

We may disclose personally identifiable information you provide via this site to third parties, but only:

  1. To Service Providers we use to support our business, such as technical support, data delivery services, and financial institutions, in which case we will require such third parties to agree to treat it in accordance with this Privacy Policy and use it for the same purposes;
  2. In connection with the sale, assignment, or other transfer of the business of this web site to which the information relates, in which case we will require any such buyer to agree to treat it in accordance with this Privacy Policy and use it for the same purposes;
  3. To respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, to establish or exercise our legal rights or, defend against legal claims and if in our judgment in such circumstances disclosure is required or appropriate;
  4. If we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of Profy’s Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law. The collection, use, and disclosure of information contemplated in this Privacy Policy may involve a transfer of the information to jurisdictions located outside your country of residence that may not have equivalent laws and rules regarding personally identifiable information. In these cases, you will be asked to consent to such transfers and disclosures in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  5. Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your personal information may be shared with third parties or used for a purpose incompatible with the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected, and you will be able to prevent the sharing of this information by opting out.

Profy may share aggregate information (in contrast to personally identifiable information) with advertisers, business partners, sponsors, and other third parties. We will not share personally identifiable information with third parties except for the above mentioned without your express consent.

**Information Protection**

Profy uses physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect personal information about you. Your Profy Account Information is also password-protected. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by breach of such firewalls and secure server software. This web site takes reasonable steps to protect personally identifiable information as you transmit it to our site and to protect such information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. However, you should remember that no data transmissions over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure or error-free. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make efforts to ensure security on our systems.

If Profy learns of a security systems breach we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using this web site or providing personal information to us you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy and administrative issues relating to your use of this site. Profy may post a notice on our web site if a security breach occurs. Profy may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances.

**Changing your Personal Information**

You can edit your Profy Account Information at any time by accessing and editing it within your profile. However, when you update information, we often maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records. You may abandon your Profy account at any time; however, please note that some personal information, primarily your email account information, may remain in Profy’s records to the extent necessary to protect Profy’s legal interests or document compliance with regulatory requirements.

**Links to Other Sites**

This web site contains links and references to other Web sites to which this Privacy Policy does not apply. Sites referenced or linked to by Profy or its users are developed by people over whom Profy has no control. These other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit personal information. By interacting with or viewing these third party sites, you are consenting to possible uses of your information by that third party which is governed by that site’s privacy policy. Therefore, we encourage you to read the Privacy Policy of every Web site you visit.
